<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Cantú]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Cantú]]></description>
        <link>http://xn--cant-tra.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 15:44:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://xn--cant-tra.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 15:44:16 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[15 Quotes That Give You Hope When You're Feeling Depressed - The Power of Ideas]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>15 Quotes That Give You Hope When You&apos;re Feeling Depressed - The Power of Ideas</h1><p>If you&apos;re anything like the majority of people, you&apos;ve experienced depression at some point in your life. Many of us experience it regularly. It&apos;s a major problem for many people, but new research is suggesting that depression helps us to adapt to new situations. It could be that experiencing depression is positioning you to live ...</p><img src="http://thepowerofideas.ideapod.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/02/depression-1.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>http://thepowerofideas.ideapod.com/15-quotes-give-hope-youre-feeling-depressed/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">666e1c7f-1709-4f19-be59-d577deafd986</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 15:43:54 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/efa9b304-15c9-4b64-96d4-d99d5d3311b9.jpg">,<blockquote>There is a God!</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/chriscantu/status/830644472509788160</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e0b4df73-a99d-4b00-9422-88e3b16c9b89</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2017 15:04:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[About Me]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/4c3d03b9-e150-48be-9562-8200de6136d7.jpg">,<p><strong>Name</strong>: Chris Cantu</p>,<p><strong>Occupation</strong>: Software Engineering Leader</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://xn--cant-tra.com/about-me/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">e0440f82-ed38-4813-99de-28ba7c66c9cc</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 13:54:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lilianna - Still I Fly]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Teaching my Lilianna to Fly</p>,<iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fembed%2FgTH5fkOoSwc%3Ffeature%3Doembed&url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DgTH5fkOoSwc&image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.ytimg.com%2Fvi%2FgTH5fkOoSwc%2Fhqdefault.jpg&key=b7d04c9b404c499eba89ee7072e1c4f7&type=text%2Fhtml&schema=youtube" width="640" height="360" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>,<p>This video was a labor of love. I love watching my children learn and grow.  I was fortunate that my wife and I recorded these lovely moments. </p>]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gTH5fkOoSwc</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2af8485d-899e-4850-8186-14c5d3c4bdbd</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 16:19:05 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First They Marched, Now More Than 13,000 Women Are Planning to Run for Office]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<article><h1>First They Marched, Now More Than 13,000 Women Are Planning to Run for Office</h1><p>On Inauguration Weekend, an estimated 3.2 million people in hundreds of cities across the country took to the streets to protest the incoming president. More than 400,000 people marched in Washington, D.C., similar numbers turned out in New York and Los Angeles, and even in Houston, Phoenix, New Orleans, Santa Fe, and Reno, marchers numbered in the tens of thousands.</p><img src="http://pixel.nymag.com/imgs/fashion/daily/2017/01/30/30-womens-march-politics.w1200.h630.jpg"></article>]]></description>
            <link>https://apple.news/A65MR2NnyRJq8D66B-iMRTQ</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">66e1bcf6-e109-4f07-931b-423c05e6822e</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 16:11:29 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Give & Take]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Give &amp; Take</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/696b7442-92a4-4ba9-9505-2c97bb966b78.jpg" title="Give &amp; Take">,<p>In the spirit of “One Team” , I thought I would share a book I finished recently, <a href="http://a.co/8ps6BGB" title="">Give and Take: Why Helping Others Drives Our Success</a> by Dr. Adam Grant. Dr. Grant describes three basic reciprocity styles; Givers, Takers and Matchers .</p>,<p>Dr. Grant performed extensive research how people’s reciprocity styles impacted their long term career success. Interestingly, Givers ranked both the lowest and highest most successful professionals. How one choses to gives has a direct impact on their success.</p>,<p>Since I found the book so though provoking, I thought I would share some of my learnings.</p>,<h2>Why Giving Matters</h2>,<h3>Universal Value</h3>,<p>According to Dr. Grant, giving or being giving of oneself is universally valued and encouraged throughout the world. Givers are praised in all walks of life and cultures. The most renown givers are celebrated often using their examples to inspire us.</p>,<h3>Its Contagious</h3>,<p>When Matchers interact with Givers, the Matchers act more like Givers. Matchers becomes givers and spread the reciprocity style in their community. Additionally, Takers in the same environment attempt to conform. These takers adjust their style to that of a Matcher or even Givers. In other words, Giving begets more giving.</p>,<h3>Givers See Potential</h3>,<p>Givers look for opportunities to pass on their knowledge and experience to others. Since givers are in more open frame of mind, they tend to recognize team mates with potential that others may ignore. As a result, givers tend to make great coaches and mentors.</p>,<h2>Successful &amp; Unsuccessful Givers</h2>,<p>Now that one can recognize the value in developing a giving reciprocity style in business, there are several tips I would like to share regarding “Successful” and “Unsuccessful” givers.</p>,<h3>Givers &amp; Saints</h3>,<p>Choosing a giving reciprocity style in work does not require one to seek Saint hood or lack personal goals. Unsuccessful givers often do not communicate their career ambitions or seek them out.. Conversely, successful givers often have very ambitious career goals and actively pursue them. The most successful givers often look for ways to align their giving with their goals. A great example would be developing expertise in a particular area and then training other team members. Another option would be to document a difficult process. This type of giving has a multiplier effect bringing up the team while simultaneously encouraging recognition for the givers contributions.</p>,<h3>Givers &amp; Door mats</h3>,<p>Givers are often viewed as door mats or push overs. Successful givers break away from this stereotype by creating boundaries. Unsuccessful givers leverage only one reciprocity style. Successful givers will engage with team members of a variety of reciprocity styles. Unsuccessful givers interact with Takers as they do anyone else. Takers utilize this opportunity to benefit as much as possible. These unsuccessful givers fail to recognize the relationship as it is; one sided. This relationship often leaves the unsuccessful givers frustrated and distraught. Successful givers recognize Takers and modify their styles to that of a Matcher. This change allows the Successful givers to balance the relationship and allowing for more opportunities to give to others.</p>,<h3>Givers &amp; Burnout</h3>,<p>Many unsuccessful givers suffer from burn out. These givers tend to focus all of their efforts in a single area; such as their jobs or places of employment. As a result of this single focus, the unsuccessful givers languish and never find a way to replenish themselves. Successful givers find methods to replenish their energies and destress. Curiously, the most successful methods include a different form of giving. For example, a teacher from “Teach for America” rejuvenated herself every week by volunteering to prepare other new teachers for the program. The change in context reinvigorated her and help her manage burnout.</p>,<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>,<p>Even though we value giving in our personal lives; we often change our style when interacting in our professional lives. We view professional engagements as zero sum or winner take all, switching to a Matcher or Taker style. I argue that this change in our nature causes unnecessary stress in our professional lives. Aligning our professional lives with our personal values is achievable and should be sought out regularly.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://xn--cant-tra.com/give-and-take/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">9263c286-53a0-4679-ad9e-f2a289cef258</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2017 00:52:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grit & Mindsets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Recently, I finished the book, "<em>Grit: The Power of Passion and Perseverance</em>" by Dr. Angela Duckworth. In my quest to become a better husband and father, I have read multiple books on positive psychology, the importance of mindset and overcoming struggle.</p>,<p>In my readings, fixed versus growth mindsets has been a common topic. Individuals with fixed mindsets view their own abilities and skills as pre-determined or stagnant. Demonstrating this view one may hear a student say, "I am just not that good at math." Individuals with growth mindsets believe their abilities can be improved. People with growth mindsets are typically more successful and happy in their lives.</p>]]></description>
            <link>http://xn--cant-tra.com/growth-and-fixed-mindsets/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d3999d35-9811-4e54-ab7c-ef4ca9bf06fe</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 11:48:48 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I have been wanting to build a blog for some time. I have had tumblr sites, google pages, etc. None of these mediums seemed to click for me. The tools lacked the refinement and ease of use I was looking for. </p>,<p>I am hoping to take advantage of Grid's new platform to create a place to express my ideas and thoughts. </p>]]></description>
            <link>http://xn--cant-tra.com/first-post/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">a8fe4754-322d-4069-a99b-1bc7405ebbbd</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 02:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>